## Dominic J Mitchell

Front End Web Designer & Developer 1-401-440-3243 Providence, RI Area

dominic.joseph.mitchell.2018@gmail.com www.linkedin.com/in/dominic-j-mitchell https://github.com/DominicJosephMitchell

Full Stack developer, specializing in front end web design UI/UX. Outgoing, enthusiastic business professional who is a technophile, cyberjunkie. Why I enjoy tech: The drive to succeed, the passion for learning, development of new skills, and the knowledge gained. "The world of programming is never ending. New technologies are constantly being crafted and we, as developers, need to keep up with these advancements or be left behind." Graduate of: (IEL) Institute of Entrepreneurial & Leadership, Rhode Coders Web Development, and (GA) General Assembly. With 30 years experience in construction, management, leadership, and eight years technology skills.

**Employment History** 

Web Design & Developer Fellow GA – General Assembly 10/2018-01/2019

\*Twelve week web development immersive program (600hrs plus)

Advanced Support Center Engineer I Cox Communications 01/2013-06/2018

\*Lead and trainer, tester new deployments, procedure development, voice, data, video support, networking

Applications Specialist – III Lead/Trainer Up-Source 01/2012-12/2012

\*Supporting 3<sup>rd</sup> party software and hardware applications: troubleshooting, break fix, install.

Consultant/Tech TMC 11/2010-01/2012

\*Advice and expertise: management, structure and strategy, IT, marketing, design, build-outs.

Founder / Entrepreneur Mitchell Construction Inc 04/2004-11/2010

\*Design/development, sales, consulting, marketing strategies, project management, leadership.

## **Education**

Institute – of – Entrepreneurial & Leadership 2018

\*HTML – CSS – JavaScript Web Design & Development

New Horizons Computer Learning Center 2011

\*A+, Net+, Sec+, MCP&MCDST Network Support Technician

Community College of Rhode Island 2003

\*Associates in Arts Degree

## **Technical Skills**

Proficient: Familiar:

HTML, CSS, wire-frames, Bootstrap,

Scrum/Agile, Git-Hub, Bash, express.js,

React, JavaScript, Mongoose, MongoDB

Handlebars, AWS, Ruby on Rails, SQL
back-end API's, SASS, Ajax, jQuery
JSON, Node.js

## Web Development Projects https://dominicjosephmitchell.github.io/DJMPortfolio/

\*Trails: Welcome to Southern New England Trails, create an index of the trails that you have experienced. (using HTML/CSS/React//MongoDB/Mongoose, and express.js)

\*Bucket List: Things you'd love to do with your life, Let's get 'em on paper! Integrate with a third-party location-based API to allow users to search for a location or venue to add to their bucket list items.

(using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Leaflet (map), Ajax, MongoDB, Mongoose and express.js)

- \* Tic Tac Toe: A custom front-end JavaScript game engine which connects with a third-party API.
- \* Vacations: Multi-page user experience designed photo album for your viewing pleasure. (using HTML, CSS)
- \* Family Tree: Ancestry database for creation and storing of family data. Add your family tree.

(using HTML, CSS, JavaScript)